Guide to the Burkina Faso Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Burkina Faso collection
1963-2004
1963-1997
MS 1505
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.27
(5 boxes)
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to cultural, political, and social conditions in Burkina Faso.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Transferred from the African Collection Curator.
Associated Materials
African Collection (MS 605); Pamphlet Collection (MS 1351); African Postcard Collection (MS 1575). Manuscripts and Archives, Yale University Library.
Arrangement
The materials are arranged by accession.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of printed material and photographs relating to cultural, political, and social conditions in Burkina Faso.
Burkina Faso -- Politics and government; Burkina Faso -- Social conditions; Photographs -- Burkina Faso; Union de lutte communiste (Burkina Faso)
- Original Accession, 1963-1991
  - Political organizations: journals; press releases; magazines; printed materials, 1972-1991 (Box 1, Folder 1 - 4)
  - Non-political organizations: journals; newsletters; printed materials, 1973-1989 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Government documents; journals; releases, 1974-1991 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Institute of Current World Affairs: newsletters, 1984 February 25-1985 January 7 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Periodicals, 1987-1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - "Images de la Haute Volta": photographs, 1963 March 10 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Village life: photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Additional Material, 1989-1997; Accession 1996-M-016
  - Centre d'Études Économiques et Sociales d'Afrique Occidentale (CESAO) Collection "La Vie Civique"
    - "Ma Commune et Moi," no. 1, 1995 January (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - "Construire La Nation," no. 2, 1997 March
  - Direction de la Gestion et de l'Animation des Salles de Spectacles (DGASS), programme, [1989] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - FESPACO (Festival,14th, Panafricain du Cinéma et de la Télévision de Ouagadougou), brochure, 1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional Material, 1967-2002; Accession 2000-M-011
  - Kibaré: Organe d'Information du Burkina Faso, no. 32, 1991 November 21, 22 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Parti Pour l'Unité National et le Développement (P.U.N.D.), "Statuts et Manifest", undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Movement Communiste International (MCI), Union de Lutte Communiste (ULC), 1979 April 11, 1981 January (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - SIAO 2002 (Salon International de l'Artisanat de Ouagadougou), "African Handicraft and Environment", 2002 October 25-November 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - "Visages d'Afrique: Organe Culturel du Cercle d'Activités Littéraires et Artistiques de Haute-Volta," special edition and no. 8, 1967, 1970 October (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Additional Material, 1978-2004; Accession 2010-M-094
  - Magazines
    - Le Démocrate, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Le Fédéraliste, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - La Famme, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Le Patriote, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Echos Oubritenga, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Minisère de la Défense Populaire: Bulletin mensuel d'information No. 005, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Tengembiiga, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Conscience du peuple, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Manegda, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Echo de la Jad, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Informations, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lolowulen, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Lutte Communiste, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Discovery (FESPACO), 2001, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Journal du Jeudi, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Carrefour Africain, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - West African Economic and Monetary Union (UEMOA) flyer, 2001 March (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Additional material, 2000s; Accession 2015-M-001
  - Printed material, 2000s (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Posters, 2000s (Folder 2)